today we're going to make an Affogato,
which is a combination of ice cream and
espresso served in Italy it's
delicious if you've never had
it we're going to use the Ninja Creami so
it's going to be nice and [Music] quick
Those of you that are Italian will know what this
is anyway but those that have never heard of it an
avocato is essentially a shot of espresso
poured over the top of vanilla ice cream
normally um you have it at breakfast at lunch
at dinner literally whenever you want it it's
a glorious thing we've had it um in quite a
few places in the world actually and it's it's
in it's an incredible treat you can't have
it all the time you shouldn't eat ice cream
all the time but hey some of us do so the other
week I made the half and half gelato the lemon
with valona white chocolate glorious and I did
the hazelnut version as well so it you knows
if you want to know how to make this base I
shall put a link up here somewhere and just
go and watch that I'm not going to talk through
it all again it's super easy it's half and half
in condensed milk plush your flavoring little
bit of invert sugar corn syrup but you know me
I don't like just doing boring stuff man that
truck's loud so what we're going to do today
is get these score this is kind of like dime
bars um I prefer score over dime controversial
I know but let's just look at the flavors we got
hazelnut this toffee is Armond pieces in it tiny
little flexs so I made hazelnut it's got It's
like a Nutty toffee kind of thing going on in
here so we're going to go hazelnut gelato with
score pieces caramel sauce hazelnut espresso
drooling yet right let's just let's chat more do
let's get a board and before we get stuck into
this let's take
some of our score mini score pieces
chop those up we want these quite
small right with that in
mind time to get the gelato
[Music] going hazelnut gelato
this just used a alcohol-based
extract it's been in the freezer for literally
ever straight
arm [Music]
noise right stage one done out we go
spoon make a div it in the middle cut
all the way down to the bottom
like so and let's get our score
pieces in there it doesn't have to
be exact just get it in score pieces
in and mix in now before I mix that in
whilst this is happening I am going to
do a shot of hazelnut espresso by Roso [Music]
Cafe I don't know why the mixing takes longer
than a bloody churn but it does all right we're
done with that let's just get this out of the way
like that quick tidy up this is super super
simple there we
go we've got our hazelnut espresso we've got our
score gelato half and half
gelato don't you know and let's
okay fancy ass
scoop like
so a balanced recipe so this can go back in
a freezer and you've got a score hazelnut
gelato [Music] and now we are simply
going to pour our espresso over the
top finally a bit of caramel syrup
sauce thumbnail and a hazelnut
espresso poured over a hazelnut score
gelato with caramel syrup that's [Music]
good honestly I could just eat this for [Music]
hours the score pieces really nice texture lovely
caramel flavor little touch of chocolate in
there the hazelnut gelato is delicious it's
smooth it's creamy it's got a wonderful hazelnut
flavor the hazelnut espresso over the top it just
boosts that flavor it's got that hazelnut
underlying flavor to it it's not too strong
so you get that bitterness of the coffee cup
through the ice cream and finally the caramel
syrup paper top just highlights the flavor of
the skore bar in there really oh God if you've
never had an afato then please do it thanks
very much for clicking on the afato recipe
super easy in your Ninja creamy don't forget to
like And subscribe and I'll see you next time
[Music]